Mehrnoosh Sameki

Research Assistant - Image and Video Computing Group

Boston, MA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Mehrnoosh-Sameki/bad04ecbdb2447ff

§ Expert in developing state-of-the-art human computation and crowdsourcing platforms

§ Highly Interested in data analysis, machine learning, human computation, human computer interaction, medical/biomedical imaging.

software design and development

§ Experienced in software development for over 9 years

§ Great social and communication skills

Willing to relocate to: Philadelphia, NY

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Image and Video Computing Group - September 2012 to Present

- Hybrid Crowd-Machine Systems to Segment and Track Objects in Biomedical Images and Videos
- o Developed and implemented a crowdsourcing platform to combine efforts of crowd workers and algorithms to segment and track cells in phase contrast and fluorescence images and videos (Python, Scikit-learn, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Matlab).
- ICORD: A Dynamic System for Intelligent Collection of Redundant Data in Crowdsourcing
- o Developed and implemented a new data collection mechanism in crowdsourcing platforms to dynamically evaluate the quality of crowd work and determine if the annotation accuracy is satisfactory or if a higher-quality annotation should be

sought out in redundant rounds of crowdsourcing (Python, Scikit-learn, Weka).

- Human Behavior Characterization in Crowdsourcing: Using Implicit Behavioral Clues to Predict Image Segmentation Quality
- o Developed a machine learning model to predict the quality of a crowd-submitted image segmentation using a collection of behavioral clues (Python, Scikit-learn, Weka, Matlab).
- Analysis of Political Discourse in Twitter Using Machine Learning and Crowdsourcing
- o Designed a human computation framework to conduct sentiment, topic, and attribute analyses of political tweets (Python,

Scikit-learn, HTML, CSS).

US Permanent Resident

(617) 669-0223 • sameki@bu.edu • 45 Stuart Street, Boston MA 02116

Software Engineering Intern

Google Research - San Francisco, CA - May 2016 to August 2016

Involved in research, formulation and data analysis of a human computation framework to predict the quality of an answer in a

Community Question Answering setting. Mentor: Dr. Praveen Paritosh

Software Engineering Intern

Google Research - San Francisco, CA - June 2015 to September 2015

Involved in research, formulation and implementation of a human computation framework to better understand diverse question

answer content in Community Question Answering websites (Recognized in P 8). Mentor: Dr. Praveen Paritosh

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Boston University - Boston, MA 2012 to Present

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering

Sharif University of Technology - Tehran, IR 2007 to 2012

SKILLS

CSS (4 years), HTML (4 years), JAVASCRIPT (4 years), MATLAB (4 years), PYTHON (4 years), Java (8 years), C (8 years), Machine Learning (4 years), Human Computer Interaction (4 years), Human Computation and Crowdsourcing (4 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages and Web Technologies: Java, Python, C, C++, JavaScript, Django, HTML, CSS
- Data Analysis Tools: Scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Matlab, Weka